<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
  - SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024-2026 [ernolf] Raphael Gradenwitz
  - SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2018-2019 Gerben
  - SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-only
-->
<info xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://apps.nextcloud.com/schema/apps/info.xsd">
    <id>files_sharing_raw</id>
    <name>Raw Fileserver</name>
    <summary>Serves files on the World Wide Web</summary>
    <description>
Raw Fileserver simply returns any requested file, so you can link directly to a file itself (i.e. without any of NextCloud's interface around it). This enables you to host static web pages, rss feeds, images or other files, for example to link/embed them elsewhere on the web.

For security and privacy, the content is served with a [Content-Security-Policy][] header.

[Content-Security-Policy]: https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Content-Security-Policy

The Content-Security-Policy (CSP) is configurable via the system config key `raw_csp`, allowing different policies per share token, path, file extension, or MIME type (with a safe hardcoded fallback).

## Usage

The common usage is to first share a file and enable public access through a link. In the Advanced settings of this share (in the right sidebar), the Raw link must be enabled. If the share link is `https://my-nextcloud/s/aBc123DeF456xyZ`, then this app will provide access to the raw file at `https://my-nextcloud/raw/aBc123DeF456xyZ`.  If the share is a folder, the files within it are accessible as e.g. `https://my-nextcloud/raw/aBc123DeF456xyZ/path/to/file`.

A user can also access their own private files. For example, a file named `test.html` in anansi's Documents folder would be available at `https://my-nextcloud/raw/u/anansi/Documents/test.html`.

Tokens must be explicitly allowed for raw access. This can be done either via the UI in the share's advanced settings, or by whitelisting them in the config.php file.

## Caching and conditional requests

`files_sharing_raw` supports conditional requests and cache validation:

- **ETags (`ETag` / `If-None-Match`)**: The app generates an `ETag` (preferred: mtime+size; fallback: content hash). If the client sends `If-None-Match` and the tag matches, the server responds with `304 Not Modified` and no body.
- **Last-Modified (`Last-Modified` / `If-Modified-Since`)**: When possible the app sets the `Last-Modified` header from the file's modification time (mtime). `If-Modified-Since` is honored when `If-None-Match` is not present. For convenience the server accepts either an RFC-style HTTP-date or a plain Unix timestamp in `If-Modified-Since`.
- **Cookie behavior**: The app removes PHP-set `Set-Cookie` headers for the current response to avoid sending cookies to clients.
</description>
    <version>0.5.0</version>
    <licence>agpl</licence>
    <author mail="raphael.gradenwitz@googlemail.com">[ernolf] - Raphael Gradenwitz</author>
    <namespace>FilesSharingRaw</namespace>
    <category>files</category>
    <repository type="git">https://github.com/ernolf/files_sharing_raw</repository>
    <bugs>https://github.com/ernolf/files_sharing_raw/issues</bugs>
    <dependencies>
        <php min-version="8.1"/>
        <nextcloud min-version="32"/>
    </dependencies>
</info>
